Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome to EnglishPod.
欢迎来到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today, we're back bringing you another great lesson, an intermediate lesson.
今天，我们回来为大家带来另一堂精彩的课程，一堂中级课程。
That's right, about one of my favorite subjects.
没错，关于我最喜欢的话题之一。
We're talking about food.
我们在谈论食物。
Exactly.
没错。
So, on this occasion, we're going to be talking about food.
所以，这次我们要讨论食物。
So let's preview some words on Vocabulary Preview.
那么，我们先在词汇预览中预览一些单词。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
We have three words for you today.
今天我们为你准备了三个单词。
And the first word is head chef.
第一个词是“主厨”。
Head chef.
主厨。
So, what is a head chef?
那么，什么是主厨？
Well, in a professional kitchen, this is the boss of the kitchen or the leader of the kitchen.
嗯，在专业厨房里，这是厨房的老板或领导者。
Okay.
好的。
So the head chef is the main cook.
所以主厨是主要的厨师。
Yes, but he doesn't cook.
是的，但他不亲自下厨。
But he doesn't cook.
但他不亲自下厨。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
好吧。
So if he doesn't cook, who's the one that does the cooking?
那如果他不下厨，谁来做菜呢？
That brings us to our second word, sous chef.
这就引出了我们的第二个词，“副主厨”。
Sous chef.
副主厨。
S-O-U-S.
S-O-U-S。
So the S is silent because it's like a French word.
所以S不发音，因为它像是一个法语词。
Yeah, something like that.
嗯，差不多吧。
Okay.
好的。
So the sous chef is the second in line to the head chef.
所以副主厨是主厨之下的第二把手。
Yeah, he's the number two.
是的，他是二号人物。
Number two.
二号人物。
So he's basically the one that's doing some of the work in the kitchen.
所以他基本上是厨房里做实际工作的人。
Yeah.
是的。
Now let's take a look at our last word, cuisine.
现在我们来看看最后一个词，“烹饪”。
Cuisine.
烹饪。
So this is an interesting word.
这是个有趣的词。
What exactly does it mean?
它到底是什么意思？
Well, it basically means cooking, right?
嗯，它基本上就是烹饪的意思，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
It's the art of cooking.
它是烹饪的艺术。
So for example, I can say French food.
比如，我可以说“法国菜”。
Yeah.
是的。
Or French cuisine.
或者“法国烹饪”。
French cuisine, which includes all the food.
法国烹饪，包括所有的食物。
Yeah.
是的。
And this is also the major that people study in college to become a chef.
这也是人们在大学里学习成为厨师的专业。
Yeah.
是的。
You study cuisine.
你学习烹饪。
And cuisine is a noun, right?
烹饪是名词，对吧？
It's a noun.
它是名词。
Okay.
好的。
So I think we're ready to dive into our dialogue.
所以我想我们准备好进入对话了。
What exactly is going on?
具体发生了什么？
Well, we're in a restaurant and it's a really busy night.
嗯，我们在一个餐厅里，今晚非常忙碌。
And so we're going to listen to what is happening in the kitchen.
所以我们要听听厨房里发生了什么。
Right away, sir.
马上就来，先生。
Your order will be ready shortly.
您的餐点很快就会准备好。
Jean-Pierre, we have another special for table seven.
Jean-Pierre，七号桌又有一份特色菜。
I'm working as fast as I can.
我已经尽力在做了。
We are really in the weeds.
我们真的忙得不可开交。
Where is my sous chef?
我的副主厨在哪？
Luc, I need you to peel more potatoes.
Luc，我需要你多削些土豆皮。
Marie, chop some onions and carrots for the stew.
Marie，切些洋葱和胡萝卜做炖菜。
Jean-Pierre, another special.
Jean-Pierre，又一份特色菜。
We're really packed tonight.
今晚我们真的客满了。
We're running low on wine.
我们的酒快用完了。
Is there any left in the cellar?
地窖里还有剩的吗？
Sorry I'm late, everyone.
抱歉，我迟到了，各位。
Wow, we're really doing well tonight.
哇，今晚我们干得真不错。
Harry, stop talking and get over here.
Harry，别说话了，过来这边。
I need some sautéed and the fish needs to be butchered and buttered.
我需要翻炒一下，鱼也需要剔骨和涂黄油。
Okay, I'm on it.
好的，我马上处理。
Jean-Pierre, table seven has requested to see the chef.
Jean-Pierre，七号桌要求见厨师。
I think there are food critics from Cuisine Magazine.
我想他们是《美食杂志》的美食评论家。
Okay, so a busy night here at this restaurant.
好的，所以这家餐厅今晚很忙。
I know.
我知道。
It sounds like there's a lot of pressure on this chef, Jean-Pierre.
听起来这位厨师Jean-Pierre压力很大。
Yeah, you can tell in his voice that he's really stressed out.
是的，从他的声音里能听出他真的很紧张。
Okay, let's take a look at some of this kitchen vocabulary that we found in Language Takeaway.
好的，我们来看看在“语言要点”中找到的一些厨房词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, well, we've got five words for you today.
好的，今天我们准备了五个词。
And the first one is peel.
第一个是“削皮”。
Peel.
削皮。
P-E-E-L.
P-E-E-L。
So, this is a verb and it means to...
所以，这是一个动词，意思是……
Remove the outside skin.
去掉外面的皮。
Okay, so for example, when you're going to eat a banana...
好的，比如，当你准备吃香蕉时……
You must peel it first.
你必须先削皮。
You must peel it.
你必须削皮。
You got to take away the yellow skin.
你得去掉那层黄色的皮。
What else do you peel?
还有什么需要削皮？
Oranges, potatoes...
橙子、土豆……
Potatoes, like in the dialogue.
土豆，就像对话里那样。
What else can you peel?
还有什么可以削皮？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Carrots.
胡萝卜。
Some people peel their tomatoes.
有些人会给西红柿削皮。
I don't know why.
我不知道为什么。
Yeah, it is kind of weird.
是啊，有点奇怪。
All right, now let's take a look at our next word.
好的，现在我们来看看下一个词。
Chop.
切。
So, again, another verb and it means to...
所以，又是一个动词，意思是……
It means to cut food into pieces.
意思是将食物切成块。
So, if you're going to eat carrots, first you got to chop them.
所以，如果你要吃胡萝卜，首先得切碎它们。
Exactly.
没错。
Right, you can't put a whole carrot in...
对，你不能把整根胡萝卜放进……
In your soup.
放进你的汤里。
In your soup or in your rice.
放进你的汤或米饭里。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, chop.
好的，切。
Okay, our next word, stirred.
好的，下一个词，“搅拌过的”。
Yeah, this is the past participle of the word stir.
是的，这是动词“搅拌”的过去分词。
Okay, so the verb stir.
好的，所以动词是“搅拌”。
Stir.
搅拌。
So, when you stir something...
所以，当你搅拌某物时……
Imagine you have a big pot and you've got a long spoon.
想象你有一个大锅和一把长勺。
You move the spoon around in circles.
你拿着勺子绕圈搅动。
So, you're stirring the pot.
所以你在搅拌锅里的东西。
You're mixing.
你在混合。
To stir is very similar to mix.
“搅拌”和“混合”很相似。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So, you just move the food around.
所以，你只是搅动食物。
Move the food around.
搅动食物。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, our next word, butchered.
好的，下一个词，“剔骨过的”。
Again, the past participle of the verb butcher.
又是动词“剔骨”的过去分词。
Okay, butcher.
好的，剔骨。
Butcher.
剔骨。
Now, this verb to butcher something, it's when you remove all the bones and all the
这个动词“剔骨”，是指从肉中去除所有骨头和内脏。
organs from the meat.
没错。
Exactly.
是的。
So, you cut up the meat.
所以，你把肉切好。
And this is interesting because it's also a noun.
这很有趣，因为它也是名词。
Right.
对。
A butcher is a person who cuts up meat.
“屠夫”是切肉的人。
Okay, so it's really easy.
好的，所以很简单。
A butcher butchers meat.
屠夫切肉。
Yes.
是的。
All right, our last word, buttered.
好的，最后一个词，“涂了黄油的”。
Buttered.
涂了黄油的。
Okay, so buttered, this is weird.
好的，“涂了黄油的”，这有点奇怪。
I know.
我知道。
Normally, we all know the noun butter, but here it's acting as a verb.
通常，我们都知道名词“黄油”，但这里它用作动词。
Okay.
好的。
So, when you butter something, you spread or put butter on it.
所以，当你给某物涂黄油时，就是把黄油涂抹在上面。
Okay.
好的。
So, to put butter on something.
所以，就是把黄油放在某物上。
So, you can butter a piece of bread.
所以，你可以给一片面包涂黄油。
Exactly.
没错。
Or in this case, the fish is being buttered.
或者在这个例子里，鱼被涂上了黄油。
Sounds delicious.
听起来很美味。
Okay, now we're ready to listen to our dialogue for the second time.
好的，现在我们准备好听第二遍对话了。
We're going to slow it down a little bit so it's easier to understand.
我们会放慢速度，这样更容易理解。
Right away, sir.
马上就来，先生。
Your order will be ready shortly.
您的餐点很快就会准备好。
Jean-Pierre, we have another special for table seven.
Jean-Pierre，七号桌又有一份特色菜。
I'm working as fast as I can.
我已经尽力在做了。
We are really in the weeds.
我们真的忙得不可开交。
Where is my sous-chef?
我的副主厨在哪？
Luc?
Luc？
I need you to peel more potatoes.
我需要你多削些土豆皮。
Marie, chop some onions and carrots for the stew.
Marie，切些洋葱和胡萝卜做炖菜。
It's not possible.
这不可能。
I'm fed up.
我受够了。
Jean-Pierre, another special.
Jean-Pierre，又一份特色菜。
We're really packed tonight.
今晚我们真的客满了。
We're running low on wine.
我们的酒快用完了。
Is there any left in the cellar?
地窖里还有剩的吗？
Whoa, sorry I'm late, everyone.
哇，抱歉，我迟到了，各位。
Wow, we are really doing well tonight.
哇，今晚我们干得真不错。
Harry, stop talking and come over here.
Harry，别说话了，过来这边。
I need this sauce stirred and the fish needs to be butchered and buttered.
我需要这酱汁搅拌一下，鱼也需要剔骨和涂黄油。
Okay, I'm on it.
好的，我马上处理。
Jean-Pierre, table seven has requested to see the chef.
Jean-Pierre，七号桌要求见厨师。
I think they are food critics from Cuisine Magazine.
我想他们是《美食杂志》的美食评论家。
Okay, so that seems to be a little bit better.
好的，这样听起来好多了。
And hey, I noticed that there's a lot of really great kitchen words in here, like words that
嘿，我注意到这里有很多很棒的厨房词汇，比如你在专业厨房里常听到的词。
you commonly hear in a professional kitchen.
是的。
Okay, so let's take a look at these kitchen words in Fluency Builder.
好的，那我们来看看“流利度构建”中的这些厨房词汇。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right, we've got three phrases.
好的，我们有三个短语。
And the first one is in the weeds.
第一个是“忙得不可开交”。
In the weeds.
忙得不可开交。
So when you're in the weeds, you're so, so busy and you can't do all the work you need
所以当你“in the weeds”时，你非常非常忙，无法按时完成所有需要做的工作。
to do on time.
按时完成。
Okay, so in the weeds, it means that you're really busy.
好的，所以“in the weeds”意思是你真的很忙。
Yes.
是的。
And you can't finish everything.
而且你无法完成所有事情。
And you have too much to do.
你有太多事情要做。
Yep.
对。
In the weeds.
忙得不可开交。
Okay, our next word, running low on.
好的，我们的下一个词，“running low on”。
Running low on.
快用完了。
Okay, so before we get into explaining what running low on means, let's listen to some
好的，在我们解释“running low on”是什么意思之前，让我们先听一些
examples.
例子。
Example one.
例子一。
You better look for a gas station.
你最好找个加油站。
We're running low on fuel.
我们的燃料快用完了。
Example two.
例子二。
We're running low on beers.
我们的啤酒快喝完了。
Can you go out and get some?
你能出去买一些吗？
Example three.
例子三。
My flashlight is running low on battery.
我的手电筒快没电了。
Hurry up before it gets dark.
在天黑之前快点。
So basically, running low means...
所以基本上，“running low”意思是……
You don't have much of this left.
你剩下的不多了。
You don't have much of something left.
你某样东西剩下的不多了。
Yeah.
对。
So here, they're running low on wine.
所以这里，他们的酒快喝完了。
So basically...
所以基本上……
There's not much wine left.
剩下的酒不多了。
Right.
没错。
So if you listen to the examples, you could also be running low on fuel, for example,
所以如果你听这些例子，你也可以说燃料快用完了，比如
on your car, etc.
你的车上的燃料等等。
Running low on.
快用完了。
All right, and now let's take a look at our last word.
好了，现在让我们看看最后一个词。
Doing really well.
做得很好。
We are doing really well.
我们做得很好。
Doing really well.
做得很好。
So this seems to be like a pretty simple structure.
所以这看起来是一个相当简单的结构。
I mean, we know all these words, right?
我的意思是，我们都认识这些词，对吧？
So why is it special?
那它有什么特别之处呢？
Well basically, if you say, I am doing really well, maybe it sounds a little bit difficult
嗯，基本上，如果你说“I am doing really well”，可能听起来有点难
to understand.
理解。
But what are you doing really well?
但你在什么方面做得很好呢？
So this is a great way of answering a question.
所以这是一个回答问题的好方法。
When somebody says, how are you?
当有人问“你好吗？”
Or how are you doing?
或者“你过得怎么样？”
You can say, I'm doing really well.
你可以说“我过得很好。”
Or I'm doing well.
或者“我过得不错。”
In your life, everything is good.
在你的生活中，一切都很好。
In your life, things are good and you're happy, basically.
在你的生活中，事情顺利，你基本上很开心。
But in this situation, in the dialogue, what's doing really well?
但在这个情境中，在对话里，什么做得很好呢？
Well, the restaurant is doing really well.
嗯，这家餐厅做得很好。
The business is doing really well.
生意做得很好。
So when he says, we're doing really well, business is good.
所以当他说“我们做得很好”时，意思是生意很好。
They're making lots of money.
他们赚了很多钱。
Exactly.
正是。
So you can use it with people.
所以你可以用它来形容人。
You can use it with businesses.
你也可以用它来形容生意。
You can say, I'm doing really well in my new job.
你可以说“我在新工作中做得很好。”
Or my son is doing really well in school.
或者“我儿子在学校表现很好。”
Okay, so you can use it in those different ways.
好的，所以你可以用这些不同的方式使用它。
Alright, well, let's listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be able to hear all
好了，让我们最后听一遍对话，这样我们就能听到所有
of these great words and phrases we just talked about.
我们刚刚讨论的这些好词和短语。
So let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
所以让我们最后听一遍对话。
So Marco, do you think this chef had a rat under his hat?
那么马可，你觉得这个厨师帽子底下有只老鼠吗？
That was a really good movie, Ratatouille, Disney, Pixar, where a rat is a cook.
那是一部非常好的电影，《料理鼠王》，迪士尼、皮克斯出品，讲一只老鼠当厨师的故事。
It's interesting, I love to cook, but I'm not very good at cooking.
很有趣，我喜欢做饭，但我不太擅长烹饪。
But it's good because for me, it helps me relieve stress.
但这很好，因为对我来说，它帮我缓解压力。
Me too, actually.
其实我也是。
You know, if I'm in a bad mood, I go home and cook something to eat and the world seems
你知道，如果我心情不好，我就回家做点吃的，世界似乎
a happier place.
变得更快乐了。
And people don't understand it because they think cooking is work.
人们不理解，因为他们觉得做饭是工作。
But for some people, it's fun.
但对有些人来说，这是乐趣。
So what about you guys?
那么你们呢？
What do you like to cook?
你喜欢做什么菜？
Do you have any particular dish that you prepare very well?
你有没有特别拿手的菜？
And if you do, please send us the recipes.
如果有，请把食谱发给我们。
Exactly, because we know that we have listeners from all over the world and of course, we
正是，因为我们知道我们有来自世界各地的听众，当然，我们
want to know what type of food you prefer.
想知道你们喜欢什么类型的食物。
So come to EnglishPod.com and post your questions, your comments and your recipes in our community
所以来EnglishPod.com，在我们的社区板块里发布你的问题、评论和食谱，
section and Erica and I will always be there.
我和埃里卡会一直在那里。
Yes, to test out your recipes as well as answer questions.
是的，来测试你的食谱以及回答问题。
For sure, if a good recipe comes along, we'll prepare it and we'll let you know how it turned
当然，如果有个好食谱，我们会做出来，然后告诉你结果
out.
如何。
All right guys, we're out of time, but we'll see you next time.
好了各位，我们时间到了，但下次再见。
Until then, goodbye.
在那之前，再见。
Bye.
拜拜。